I'm sorry about the other day.
(雪乃)この間は ごめんなさい
No problem!
(結衣)全然！ 私も帰りが遅いって
よくママに言われたりするし
My mom tells me all the time that I come home too late.
(比企谷)まッ 母ちゃんってのは
そういうもんだろ
Well, that's what moms are for.
They always have something to say.
あれこれ言いたがるもんだ
最近は受験のこともあるしな
Komachi's entrance exam is coming up,
so she and Mom have been arguing about that lately.
よく 小町と母ちゃんで
ワーワー言ってる
Oh, yeah, Komachi-chan's exam is tomorrow, huh?
ああ小町ちゃん
もう明日 受験だもんね
It gives us the day off, too.
私達も入試で休みだし
小町さんのことだから
大丈夫だとは思うけれど
If I know Komachi-san, I'm sure she'll do fine, though.
ああ
お兄ちゃんとしては心配だよね
Yeah...
But as her brother, you've gotta worry, huh?
そうなんだ 小町かわいすぎるから
絶対人気が出るだろ
Exactly.
Komachi's too cute, so she's bound to be popular, right?
男子への警戒しなきゃいけないし
何より 俺みたいな
Because of that, I'll have to watch out for boys.
Above all, I have to make sure nobody finds out she has a useless brother like me.
ろくでなしの兄がいると
知られないようにしないと…
Komachi's reputation depends on it.
小町の評判に かかわるからな
心配するとこ そこ!?
That's what you're worried about?
Also, you're assuming she'll pass?
…ていうか合格前提？
I'm not sure if that's thinking positively or negatively.
ポジティブなのか
ネガティブなのか分からないわね
あッ それって
ゆきのんの手作り？
Did you make those, Yukinon?
Y-Yes.
え ええ
昨日の夜 ちょうど作ったから
I just made them last night...
I see!
そうなんだ 私もあれから
ちょっと頑張ったけど なかなかね
I've kinda been trying since then, too, but it's not going too well.
Here, if you'd like.
これ よかったら
おおッ ありがとう！
Thanks!
Um... Just for me?
えっと 私のだけ？
<何で 目そらしてんだ？ 俺は>
Why am I averting my eyes?
ヒッキーのは？
What about Hikki's?
(足音)
よかったら
お おう
If you'd like...
S-Sure...
♬～
Later.
Okay, see ya!
じゃあな
うん またね！
Ah...
あッ…
あの…
Um...
Uh... I'm gonna go on ahead.
え～っと 私 先行くね
えっと
Uh...
どうしよっか？
What should I do?
あッ
うんッ？
Yukino-chan, I'm here to pick you up.
(陽乃)雪乃ちゃん 迎えに来たよ
Nee-san...
姉さん
迎えに来られる用なんて
ないと思うけれど
I see no reason for you to pick me up.
Mom told me to.
お母さんに言われたの
しばらく一緒に住むように
She said I should live with you for a while.
Why would she say that now?
何で そんなこと急に…
あるでしょう？ 心当たり
I think you have an idea why.
それは私が自分でやることよ
姉さんには関係ない…
That's something for me to do myself.
It has nothing to do with you.
雪乃ちゃんに
自分なんてあるの？➡
Do you even have your own "self"?
今まで 私がどうするかを見て
決めてきたのに➡
I've watched you all this time to decide what should be done.
自分の考えなんて話せるの？
Can you really talk about your own ideas?
You've always been allowed to live as you please, haven't you?
雪乃ちゃんは いっつも
自由にさせられてきたもんね
But you haven't made any decisions on your own.
でも
自分で決めてきたわけじゃない
今だって どうふるまっていいか
分かってないんでしょ？
Even now, you don't know how to act, do you?
雪乃ちゃんは 一体どうしたいの？
What is it you want to do, Yukino-chan?
姉妹ゲンカなら
よそでやりませんか？
If you sisters are going to fight, could you do it elsewhere?
This can't even be called a fight.
こんなのケンカにもならないよ
We've never fought once, you know.
昔からケンカなんて
したことないんだから
Whatever it is, this isn't the place for it.
どっちにしろ こんなとこで
する話じゃないでしょ
U-Um...
あ あの
We... We have thought on our own.
ちゃんと ちゃんと考えてます
ゆきのんも 私も
Yukinon and I both have.
そッ じゃあ
帰ったら聞かせてもらうね
Oh?
Then tell me all about it when you get home.
どうせ 雪乃ちゃんが
帰れる場所なんて
You only have one home you can come back to, after all.
一つしか ないんだし
え… えっと
U-Um...
そうだ うち来る？
Oh, I know!
Wanna come to my place?
<言われるままに来てみたものの>
She told me to come,
so I did, but now...
ごめんなさい
迷惑をかけてしまって
I'm sorry to trouble you.
Don't worry! It's no trouble!
全然 気にしないで
(結衣の母)そうよ～
気にしなくても全然いいんだから
That's right! You don't have to worry at all!
ヒッキー君 ね
は はあ…
You're Hikki-kun, right?
Uh... Yeah...
結衣から いっつも聞いてるのよ～
Yui talks about you all the time.
Mom! You don't have to tell him that!
ママ！
余計なこと言わなくていいから
Aww, I want to talk to Hikki-kun, too!
ママも ヒッキー君とお話ししたい
そういうの いいから
That's enough!
≪(結衣の母)雪乃ちゃん
泊まってくでしょ？ お布団…
Oh, Yukinon-chan is spending the night, right?
I'll have to get out a futon.
I'll handle that!
それは私がやるし！
(結衣がドアを閉める)
何か ごめんね
Sorry about that.
ﾏﾏ ゆきのん来たの嬉しいみたいで
舞い上がっちゃって
I guess Mom's a little too excited to have you here, Yukinon.
恥ずかしいなあ
いいえ
How embarrassing...
Not at all.
仲がいいのね
ちょっとうらやましいわ
You two are very close. I'm a bit jealous.
<あの母親と あの姉だ>
With the mother and sister she has,
<雪ノ下でなくたって
うまくやるのは難しかろう>
I think anyone would have trouble, Yukinoshita or otherwise.
ごめんなさい
変な話をしてしまって
I'm sorry. That was an awkward thing to bring up.
そろそろ帰るわ
あッ それなんだけどさ
I'll head home now.
Hey, about that...
泊まってったら？
えッ けれど…
Why don't you stay over?
But...
私も よく泊めてもらってるし
帰りづらい時とか あるし
You let me stay over all the time.
And I know sometimes it's hard to go home.
Well, neither you nor your sister are thinking clearly right now.
まッ 今は
お互い冷静じゃないだろうし
I don't see a problem with taking a night to think things over.
一晩考えるってことにしたら
いいんじゃねえの？
Just give them a call first.
一応 連絡だけはしてさ
Yeah, I think that's a good idea.
うん それがいいかも
Yes... You're right.
そうね あなたの言うとおりだわ
(呼び出し中)
Hello...
もしもし
今は お互い冷静じゃないだろうし
一晩考えて 改めて話しに行くわ
Neither of us is thinking clearly right now.
I'm going to take a night to think things over, and then I'll talk to you.
一応 連絡だけ…
今の…
I just called to let you know.
She just...
Hmm... All right.
☎(陽乃)ふ～ん分かった どうせ
そこに比企谷君いるんでしょ？
Hikigaya-kun's there, isn't he?
☎代わって
Put him on.
(足音)
姉さんが話したいって
My sister wants to talk to you.
何ですか？
☎優しいね 比企谷君は
What is it?
You're such a nice guy, Hikigaya-kun.
Are you still awake?
まだ起きてる？
ええ
Yes.
ゆきのんはさ どうしたい？
私は…
What do you want to do, Yukinon?
I...
私はね したいことあるよ
I have something I want to do.
ちゃんと決めたの
I decided on it.
明日さ
Tomorrow...
デートしない？
Want to go on a date?
はい？
Pardon?
Brr, it's cold...
受験票持ったか？
消しｺﾞﾑとﾊﾝｶﾁ かえの鉛筆は？
Got your exam admission slip?
And your eraser and handkerchief?
Spare pencil?
(小町)大丈夫
行ってくるであります
I'm all set!
I'm going now!
おう 行ってらっしゃい
Yep. Off you go.
サイン コサイン…
Sine, cosine, tangent...
今日は一日降るなあ
I'm free for the whole day.
(バイブレーター着信)
おッ
Incoming call:
Yui
☎ヒッキー デートしよう
Hikki! Let's have a date!
はッ？
Huh?
えッ
あッ
If you two have plans, I'll head back...
もし あれなら
私 戻っているけれど
いいの
This is fine.
三人で 行きたいの
I want the three of us to go together.
水族園？
An aquatic park?
ここでいいのか？
うん ここなら雪も関係ないし
This is where you want to go?
Yep! The snow doesn't matter here.
アハハ サメ！
Wow, sharks!
サメね
ゆきのん 黙ってたのはごめんって
Sharks, indeed...
Yukinon! I'm sorry I didn't tell you, okay?
もっとテンション上げてこうよ～
そう言われても
Be a little more excited!
That's easy to say...
おお ハンマーヘッドシャーク
Wow! Hammerhead sharks!
何これ 写真撮っていいの？
うん うん
Huh? What? We can take pictures?
See? Even Hikki's having fun.
ほら ヒッキーも楽しそうだし
ああ…
お… な 何だ？
Wh-What?
いいえ 少し意外だっただけ
Nothing. I was just a bit surprised.
写真 サメと一緒に撮ってあげるわ
I'll take a picture of you with the sharks.
マジか？ 小町に自慢してやろう
Really? I'm gonna show this off to Komachi!
That's a "nurseryfish," it says.
ナーサリーフィッシュだって
｢泥で濁った川の中で｣
"They live in muddy rivers,
｢あまり泳ぎ回らず
生活している｣そうよ
where they don't move around too much," apparently.
ほう エビとかが目の前を通ると
Huh...
If a shrimp passes by, it'll swallow it up in an instant, huh?
一瞬で飲み込むのか
理想の生き様だな
共感してる!?
That's the ideal way to live.
You're sympathizing with it?!
言われてみれば この魚
誰かに似ているわね
Now that you mention it,
this fish does remind me of someone...
ヒキザカナ君
全然似てねえし 名前も似てねえし
Hikifishy-kun.
It's nothing like me,
and that name is nothing like mine, either.
うわ～ッ キモ～い
Ugh, it looks creepy!
そういうこと言うんじゃねえよ
一生懸命 生きてんだろ
Don't say stuff like that.
They're doing their best to survive.
でも ちょっとかわいいかも
It is kinda cute, though.
かわいいかは 置いておくにしても
愛きょうは あるわね
Whether or not it's cute aside,
it has a certain charm.
キモいって言われた時点で
かわいいも何もないんだよな～
The fact that you called it creepy means you see nothing cute about it.
へえ～ッ イヌザメだって！
Wow, "inuzame"!
ちょっとサブレっぽいかも
どこが？
They look a little like Sable!
How?
ネコザメ… 解せないわ
"Nekozame"? I don't get it.
命名するからには
ネコに似ている部分がどこかに…
Since the name means "cat shark," it must be catlike in some way...
<ほう ネコと名の付くものには
反応せざるを得ないんですね>
I see...
You have to react to anything with "cat" in the name, eh?
<マジ ネコ大好きフリスキー>
She really does love cats like they love Friskies.
It does feel a little like a cat's tongue.
手触りはネコの舌に似ているかも
That's just what shark skin feels like.
<それ ただのサメ肌だぞ>
Oh, there's a ray, too!
あッ エイもいる！
うわッ
今ヌルッてした ヌルッて！
Eww! Something was just slimy! It was slimy!
何に触ったの？ 比企谷君に？
早く手を洗ったほうがいいわ
What did you touch? Hikigaya-kun?
You should wash your hand quickly.
<ちょっと～>
Excuse me?
Don't treat me like a ray.
<人をエイ扱いするのやめてね
粘液出てないからね 俺>
I'm not covered in mucus.
ネコ ネコザメ
Neko... "Cat shark"... Cat...
ネコ ニャー いえシャーかしら
Nyaa... Or perhaps "shaa"?
<シャークの鳴き方は
シャーじゃないと思うけどな>
I'm pretty sure sharks don't say "shaa."
何だ もういいのか？
What? Done already?
うん あんまり触ると
この子達も疲れちゃうだろうし
Yeah. Getting touched too much probably makes them tired.
そうか 由比ヶ浜らしいな
I see. That's just like you.
私らしいって何だろね
What is "just like me," I wonder...
私 ヒッキーが思ってるほど
優しくないんだけどな
I'm not as nice as you think I am, really.
(ペンギンの鳴き声)
あッ ペンギンだ
ヒッキー ゆきのん 行こう
Penguins!
Hikki, Yukinon, let's go!
やだ何これ 超かわいいんですけど
Oh, God, what are those? They're so cute!
小町に写真 送んねえと
わあ すごいすごい 泳いでるよ
I've gotta send Komachi a picture.
Wow, look! They're swimming!
こうして見ると
ペンギンって鳥みたいだね
When I see them this way, penguins look like birds.
そもそも ﾍﾟﾝｷﾞﾝは鳥なのだけれど
えｯ し… 知ってたし
Penguins are birds, actually.
Shining in that blue sky
Huh? I-I knew that...
Humboldt Penguins
An airplane flies off into the horizon
.
おッ どうした？
What's up?
Something I kept caged in my heart starts stirring
中で待っているわ
I'll be waiting inside.
I lock away the feelings I want to express
Have you noticed two of the penguins cuddling?
Those two are actually mates. Once two Humboldt penguins mate,
they tend to stay with the same partner until one of them dies.
They show their affection by grooming their partner's body
and calling out to them. We hope you enjoy observing the couple's behavior.
.
Have you noticed two of the penguins cuddling?
Those two are actually mates. Once two Humboldt penguins mate,
they tend to stay with the same partner until one of them dies.
They show their affection by grooming their partner's body
and calling out to them. We hope you enjoy observing the couple's behavior.
Have you noticed two of the penguins cuddling?
Those two are actually mates. Once two Humboldt penguins mate,
they tend to stay with the same partner until one of them dies.
They show their affection by grooming their partner's body
and calling out to them. We hope you enjoy observing the couple's behavior.
Have you noticed two of the penguins cuddling?
Those two are actually mates. Once two Humboldt penguins mate,
they tend to stay with the same partner until one of them dies.
They show their affection by grooming their partner's body
and calling out to them. We hope you enjoy observing the couple's behavior.
.
Have you noticed two of the penguins cuddling?
Those two are actually mates. Once two Humboldt penguins mate,
they tend to stay with the same partner until one of them dies.
They show their affection by grooming their partner's body
and calling out to them. We hope you enjoy observing the couple's behavior.
Have you noticed two of the penguins cuddling?
Those two are actually mates. Once two Humboldt penguins mate,
they tend to stay with the same partner until one of them dies.
They show their affection by grooming their partner's body
and calling out to them. We hope you enjoy observing the couple's behavior.
Have you noticed two of the penguins cuddling?
Those two are actually mates. Once two Humboldt penguins mate,
they tend to stay with the same partner until one of them dies.
They show their affection by grooming their partner's body
and calling out to them. We hope you enjoy observing the couple's behavior.
Have you noticed two of the penguins cuddling?
Those two are actually mates. Once two Humboldt penguins mate,
they tend to stay with the same partner until one of them dies.
They show their affection by grooming their partner's body
and calling out to them. We hope you enjoy observing the couple's behavior.
Have you noticed two of the penguins cuddling?
Those two are actually mates. Once two Humboldt penguins mate,
they tend to stay with the same partner until one of them dies.
They show their affection by grooming their partner's body
and calling out to them. We hope you enjoy observing the couple's behavior.
Have you noticed two of the penguins cuddling?
Those two are actually mates. Once two Humboldt penguins mate,
they tend to stay with the same partner until one of them dies.
They show their affection by grooming their partner's body
and calling out to them. We hope you enjoy observing the couple's behavior.
Have you noticed two of the penguins cuddling?
Those two are actually mates. Once two Humboldt penguins mate,
they tend to stay with the same partner until one of them dies.
They show their affection by grooming their partner's body
and calling out to them. We hope you enjoy observing the couple's behavior.
Have you noticed two of the penguins cuddling?
Those two are actually mates. Once two Humboldt penguins mate,
they tend to stay with the same partner until one of them dies.
They show their affection by grooming their partner's body
and calling out to them. We hope you enjoy observing the couple's behavior.
Have you noticed two of the penguins cuddling?
Those two are actually mates. Once two Humboldt penguins mate,
they tend to stay with the same partner until one of them dies.
They show their affection by grooming their partner's body
and calling out to them. We hope you enjoy observing the couple's behavior.
Have you noticed two of the penguins cuddling?
Those two are actually mates. Once two Humboldt penguins mate,
they tend to stay with the same partner until one of them dies.
They show their affection by grooming their partner's body
and calling out to them. We hope you enjoy observing the couple's behavior.
.
Have you noticed two of the penguins cuddling?
Those two are actually mates. Once two Humboldt penguins mate,
they tend to stay with the same partner until one of them dies.
They show their affection by grooming their partner's body
and calling out to them. We hope you enjoy observing the couple's behavior.
.
Have you noticed two of the penguins cuddling?
Those two are actually mates. Once two Humboldt penguins mate,
they tend to stay with the same partner until one of them dies.
They show their affection by grooming their partner's body
and calling out to them. We hope you enjoy observing the couple's behavior.
.
Have you noticed two of the penguins cuddling?
Those two are actually mates. Once two Humboldt penguins mate,
they tend to stay with the same partner until one of them dies.
They show their affection by grooming their partner's body
and calling out to them. We hope you enjoy observing the couple's behavior.
Have you noticed two of the penguins cuddling?
Those two are actually mates. Once two Humboldt penguins mate,
they tend to stay with the same partner until one of them dies.
They show their affection by grooming their partner's body
and calling out to them. We hope you enjoy observing the couple's behavior.
.
Have you noticed two of the penguins cuddling?
Those two are actually mates. Once two Humboldt penguins mate,
they tend to stay with the same partner until one of them dies.
They show their affection by grooming their partner's body
and calling out to them. We hope you enjoy observing the couple's behavior.
.
Have you noticed two of the penguins cuddling?
Those two are actually mates. Once two Humboldt penguins mate,
they tend to stay with the same partner until one of them dies.
They show their affection by grooming their partner's body
and calling out to them. We hope you enjoy observing the couple's behavior.
Have you noticed two of the penguins cuddling?
Those two are actually mates. Once two Humboldt penguins mate,
they tend to stay with the same partner until one of them dies.
They show their affection by grooming their partner's body
and calling out to them. We hope you enjoy observing the couple's behavior.
.
Have you noticed two of the penguins cuddling?
Those two are actually mates. Once two Humboldt penguins mate,
they tend to stay with the same partner until one of them dies.
They show their affection by grooming their partner's body
and calling out to them. We hope you enjoy observing the couple's behavior.
Have you noticed two of the penguins cuddling?
Those two are actually mates. Once two Humboldt penguins mate,
they tend to stay with the same partner until one of them dies.
They show their affection by grooming their partner's body
and calling out to them. We hope you enjoy observing the couple's behavior.
Have you noticed two of the penguins cuddling?
Those two are actually mates. Once two Humboldt penguins mate,
they tend to stay with the same partner until one of them dies.
They show their affection by grooming their partner's body
and calling out to them. We hope you enjoy observing the couple's behavior.
.
Have you noticed two of the penguins cuddling?
Those two are actually mates. Once two Humboldt penguins mate,
they tend to stay with the same partner until one of them dies.
They show their affection by grooming their partner's body
and calling out to them. We hope you enjoy observing the couple's behavior.
.
Have you noticed two of the penguins cuddling?
Those two are actually mates. Once two Humboldt penguins mate,
they tend to stay with the same partner until one of them dies.
They show their affection by grooming their partner's body
and calling out to them. We hope you enjoy observing the couple's behavior.
Have you noticed two of the penguins cuddling?
Those two are actually mates. Once two Humboldt penguins mate,
they tend to stay with the same partner until one of them dies.
They show their affection by grooming their partner's body
and calling out to them. We hope you enjoy observing the couple's behavior.
Have you noticed two of the penguins cuddling?
Those two are actually mates. Once two Humboldt penguins mate,
they tend to stay with the same partner until one of them dies.
They show their affection by grooming their partner's body
and calling out to them. We hope you enjoy observing the couple's behavior.
.
Have you noticed two of the penguins cuddling?
Those two are actually mates. Once two Humboldt penguins mate,
they tend to stay with the same partner until one of them dies.
They show their affection by grooming their partner's body
and calling out to them. We hope you enjoy observing the couple's behavior.
Have you noticed two of the penguins cuddling?
Those two are actually mates. Once two Humboldt penguins mate,
they tend to stay with the same partner until one of them dies.
They show their affection by grooming their partner's body
and calling out to them. We hope you enjoy observing the couple's behavior.
Have you noticed two of the penguins cuddling?
Those two are actually mates. Once two Humboldt penguins mate,
they tend to stay with the same partner until one of them dies.
They show their affection by grooming their partner's body
and calling out to them. We hope you enjoy observing the couple's behavior.
Have you noticed two of the penguins cuddling?
Those two are actually mates. Once two Humboldt penguins mate,
they tend to stay with the same partner until one of them dies.
They show their affection by grooming their partner's body
and calling out to them. We hope you enjoy observing the couple's behavior.
.
Have you noticed two of the penguins cuddling?
Those two are actually mates. Once two Humboldt penguins mate,
they tend to stay with the same partner until one of them dies.
They show their affection by grooming their partner's body
and calling out to them. We hope you enjoy observing the couple's behavior.
Have you noticed two of the penguins cuddling?
Those two are actually mates. Once two Humboldt penguins mate,
they tend to stay with the same partner until one of them dies.
They show their affection by grooming their partner's body
and calling out to them. We hope you enjoy observing the couple's behavior.
Have you noticed two of the penguins cuddling?
Those two are actually mates. Once two Humboldt penguins mate,
they tend to stay with the same partner until one of them dies.
They show their affection by grooming their partner's body
and calling out to them. We hope you enjoy observing the couple's behavior.
Have you noticed two of the penguins cuddling?
Those two are actually mates. Once two Humboldt penguins mate,
they tend to stay with the same partner until one of them dies.
They show their affection by grooming their partner's body
and calling out to them. We hope you enjoy observing the couple's behavior.
Have you noticed two of the penguins cuddling?
Those two are actually mates. Once two Humboldt penguins mate,
they tend to stay with the same partner until one of them dies.
They show their affection by grooming their partner's body
and calling out to them. We hope you enjoy observing the couple's behavior.
Have you noticed two of the penguins cuddling?
Those two are actually mates. Once two Humboldt penguins mate,
they tend to stay with the same partner until one of them dies.
They show their affection by grooming their partner's body
and calling out to them. We hope you enjoy observing the couple's behavior.
.
Have you noticed two of the penguins cuddling?
Those two are actually mates. Once two Humboldt penguins mate,
they tend to stay with the same partner until one of them dies.
They show their affection by grooming their partner's body
and calling out to them. We hope you enjoy observing the couple's behavior.
.
Have you noticed two of the penguins cuddling?
Those two are actually mates. Once two Humboldt penguins mate,
they tend to stay with the same partner until one of them dies.
They show their affection by grooming their partner's body
and calling out to them. We hope you enjoy observing the couple's behavior.
.
Have you noticed two of the penguins cuddling?
Those two are actually mates. Once two Humboldt penguins mate,
they tend to stay with the same partner until one of them dies.
They show their affection by grooming their partner's body
and calling out to them. We hope you enjoy observing the couple's behavior.
.
Have you noticed two of the penguins cuddling?
Those two are actually mates. Once two Humboldt penguins mate,
they tend to stay with the same partner until one of them dies.
They show their affection by grooming their partner's body
and calling out to them. We hope you enjoy observing the couple's behavior.
they tend to stay with the same partner until one of them dies
.
And replace them with words I cannot say
they tend to stay with the same partner until one of them dies
.
(足音)
I couldn't be honest until the end
由比ヶ浜さんは？
ﾌｪｱﾘｰﾍﾟﾝｷﾞﾝの写真撮ってる
Where's Yuigahama-san?
Taking pictures of the fairy penguins.
Oh.
そう
I tangled up the thread connecting us
自由なのも いるのね
ああ あの魚はデカイしな
Some of them are moving freely...
Yeah, it's a pretty huge fish.
And cut you loose
If it has nowhere to go,
it won't find the place where it belongs.
寄る辺がなければ
自分の居場所も見つけられない
If I'd told you I was sorry
隠れて流されて
何かについていって
It'll hide, ride the current, follow something else,
見えない壁に ぶつかるの
and crash into walls it can't see.
どの魚のことだ？
Before those tears fell
Which fish are you talking about?
私のこと
Me.
If I'd told you I wanted to see you
二人とも お待たせ～
Hey, guys! Sorry for the wait!
They look kinda like fireworks, don't they?
何かさ 花火みたいだね
Before that vapor trail disappeared
They do?
そうか？
見えない？
You don't see it? Look, like that one.
ほら あれとか
ひゅーん ぱーんって
It's like, fwoom, bang...
Maybe I could've avoided this endless heartbreak
Maybe I could've been here with you
ヘヘヘ フフフ
Hello, hello, alone
近い
ヘヘヘ
You're close...
三人で見れて
I'm glad the three of us
よかった
saw this together.
ゴール！
ねえ もう１周しちゃおっか？
Goal!
Hey, want to go through again?
しねえよ 同じとこ回っても
しょうがないだろ
No.
What's the point in seeing the same stuff again?
そ そうね 少し疲れたし
H-He's right. I'm a bit tired, anyway.
そうかな 楽しいと思うけど
それに まだ時間あるし
Really? I think it'd be fun.
And we still have some time...
あッ
<不安定さを偽りながら>
A Ferris wheel disguises its instability
<ゆっくりと回り続ける>
as it keeps slowly turning around and around.
It never moves forward,
<前へ進むことはなく>
but just keeps spinning in the same spot forever.
<ただ 同じところを いつまでも>
<それでも やがて>
But still, eventually...
It's almost over.
もうすぐ終わりだね
これから どうしよっか？
帰るだろ？
What should we do now?
Aren't we going home?
そうじゃなくて
I don't mean that.
ゆきのんのこと
About Yukinon,
and about me.
それと私のこと
私達のこと
About us.
それは どういう意味？
What do you mean by that?
Hikki...
ヒッキー
これ
Here.
あの時の お礼
To thank you for that one time.
私の相談 覚えてる？
Remember when I asked for your help?
あッ
Handmade cookies...
手作りクッキー…
これを 一人で？
You made them on your own?
I screwed up a little, though.
ちょっと失敗しちゃったけどね
由比ヶ浜さん あなた すごいわ
Yuigahama-san, you are amazing.
私が 自分でやってみるって言って
I said that I'd try it on my own,
that I'd try to say it in my own way.
自分なりのやり方で
やってみるって言って
And this is what I came up with.
それが これなの
だから ただのお礼
So...
It's just to thank you.
礼なら もうもらってる
You already thanked me.
Still...
それでも
It's just to thank you.
ただの お礼だよ
私は全部欲しい
I want everything.
今も これからも
Now, and from now on...
私 ずるいんだ 卑怯な子なんだ
I'm unfair. I'm a mean person.
私はもう ちゃんと決めてる
I've made up my mind.
そう…
I see...
もし お互いの思ってること
分かっちゃったら
If we each find out how the other feels,
このままっていうのも
できないと思う
I don't think we'll be able to stay the way we are.
だから これが最後の相談
So this will be the last help we give.
私達の最後の依頼は
私達のことだよ
The last request I have for us
is about us.
ねえ ゆきのん 例の勝負の件って
まだ続いてるよね？
Hey, Yukinon, that contest we were having is still on, right?
ええ
勝った人の言うことを何でも聞く
Yes. The losers have to do whatever the winner says.
ゆきのんの 今 抱えてる問題
私 答え分かってるの
I know the answer to your problem, Yukinon.
I think it's probably the answer for all of us.
たぶん それが私達の答えだと思う
So...
それで…
If I win, I'll take everything.
私が勝ったら 全部もらう
She didn't say one specific thing.
<何一つ 具体的なことは
言わなかった>
<口に出してしまえば
確定してしまうから>
If she said it out loud, that would set in in stone.
<それを避けてきたのだ>
She's been avoiding that.
ずるいかもしんないけど
それしか思いつかないんだ
I know it's unfair...
But it's the only way I can think of.
ずっと このままでいたいなって
思うの
I want things to stay this way forever.
どうかな？
What do you think?
Yuigahama is, most likely, not wrong.
<由比ヶ浜は たぶん間違えない>
<彼女だけは ずっと
正しい答えを見ていた気がする>
I have a feeling
she's the only one who has seen the right answer all this time.
<それを受け入れてしまえば
きっと楽だろう>
Surely it would be easier to just accept it.
<けれど…>
But...
Yukinon...
ゆきのん それでいい？
Is that okay?
わた しは…
I...
<ああ これは違う 間違っている>
Yes, this is wrong.
She's wrong.
わた しは…
I...
Yukinoshita can't entrust her future to someone else.
<雪ノ下が 自分の未来を
誰かに委ねるなんて>
<そんなこと
あっていいはずがない>
There's no way that can be right.
私は…
I...
wouldn't mind tha—
それでも かまわな…
いや
No.
その提案には乗れない
I can't go along with that.
雪ノ下の問題は
雪ノ下自身が解決すべきだ
Yukinoshita should solve her own problem herself.
<由比ヶ浜結衣は 優しい女の子だ>
Yuigahama Yui is a nice girl.
<そう勝手に決めつけていた>
I had decided that for myself.
<雪ノ下雪乃は強い女の子だ>
Yukinoshita Yukino is a strong girl.
<そうやって
理想を押し付けていた>
That's the ideal I had forced onto you.
それに そんなの ただの欺瞞だろ
And that's nothing but...
a deception.
あいまいな答えとか
慣れ合いの関係とか
Vague answers and mutual back-scratching...
そういうのは いらない
I don't need any of that.
<バカなヤツだと思う>
I know I'm an idiot.
<そんなのないって
知っているのに>
I know there's no such thing.
I know that if I try to pursue it, I won't gain anything.
<突き詰めてしまったら
何も手に入らないと>
<分かっているのに>
それでも ちゃんと考えて苦しんで
But still, by thinking, agonizing, struggling...
あがいて 俺は…
I...
I thought you'd say that, Hikki.
ヒッキーなら そう言うと思った
Don't decide how I feel for me.
私の気持ちを勝手に決めないで
それに最後じゃないわ
And this isn't the last.
比企谷君
Hikigaya-kun...
We still have your request.
あなたの依頼が残ってる
あッ…
<間違っていてもいい>
It's okay to be wrong.
<そのたびに問い直して
問い続けるから>
When we are, we'll just ask again, and keep on asking.
あと もう一つ
And one more thing...
私の依頼 聞いてもらえるかしら？
Would you listen to my request?
Spring Always Comes to Life
Buried Underneath a Pile of Snow.
うん 聞かせて
Okay. Let's hear it.
♬～